Aaron Breckenridge

Summary

14 years of professional software development experience preceded by 7 years of business analyst experience of adding automation to existing business processes. Adept at all levels of the software development stack, including leadership roles, business processes, user interface design, architecture, infrastructure and implementation. An intrinsic drive to take ownership of the entire software development lifecycle.

Ruby, Postgres, Redis, Python, Swift, iOS, React, React Native, JavaScript, TypeScript, AWS, Linux, JIRA, Docker

Experience

BiggerPockets, Remote

Jan 2022 — Present

Staff Software Developer

- Improved site load and page performance to meet strict Core Web Vital targets. This led to higher SEO rankings and a large bump in organic traffic (20% YoY).
- Led a team through a site-wide navigation menu rewrite that unified several implementations into a single service-based API call. This saved engineers time and sped up turnaround times for feature releases.
- Implemented real-time push notifications on desktop and mobile.
- Created a recommendations feature that increased time-on-site by using text embeddings (OpenAI) and a vector database (Pinecone).
- Created an AB test experiment that increased signup conversions (~3.5%) by presenting a popular site utility in more places.

Theorem, Remote

Sept 2019 — Dec 2021

Senior Software Developer

- Developed non-disclosed in-store prototype digital experiences for Apple using Swift and Typescript.
- Developed iPad-based system used by retail store employees and customers for in-store AirPod and Apple Pencil engraving using React Native and Ruby.
- On-boarded customer to Theorem as the primary software developer. Brought in additional developers, trained them, and eventually transitioned the customer team to other Theorem developers.
- Worked with Theorem designers to develop new custom software that simplified team member onboarding and clarified the business processes of the customer team within Apple.
- Maintained and enhanced a suite of existing applications used to conduct an in-house corporate internship program, automatically generate business reports, interface with other Apple infrastructure, and track lab assets.

Onsite Health Diagnostics, Coppell, Texas

May 2015 — Aug 2019

Interim CTO/Lead Software Developer

- Advised executives on transition from B2E to a SaaS model and created and executed infrastructure and development plans to implement this transition.
- Crafted and implemented business processes to maintain HIPAA compliance and third-party security certifications required for contractual agreements.
- Managed and led in-house four-person software development team responsible for maintaining and enhancing our existing custom software suite.
- Managed contractors responsible for additional software development and maintaining company-owned hardware.
- Led team developing software to replace a paper-based health screening incentives program with an
 iPad-based software solution for real-time incentive results. Responsible for UX, software architecture,
 user studies, and observing and improving the screening process.

Left interim CTO position in order to refocus on full-time software development and pursue opportunities with larger teams and greater variety of projects. Hired and trained my replacement.

Geoforce, Coppell, Texas

Feb 2013 — Apr 2015

Lead Software Developer/Software Developer

- Maintained and enhanced software suite used to communicate with cellular and satellite-based asset trackers.
- Designed and implemented new software, *Rental Radar*, to track oilfield assets and combine that with asset rental information to facilitate automatic billing of rental customers.

Readyflight, Remote Aug 2012 — Feb 2013

Software Developer

- Joined this early-stage B2B SaaS startup as the third employee (second software developer) to grow software development experience.
- Designed and developed new software, *Scratch and Dent*, used for visual compliance tracking of known aircraft defects.
- Improved and extended software used to track custom aircraft maintenance programs.

Certrec, Fort Worth, Texas

Jan 2009 — Aug 2012

Software QA Analyst/Customer Services Team Manager/Technical Analyst

- Implemented a process and software to automate capturing of microfiche-based images into searchable PDFs.
- Designed and developed a new interface used by Customer Services team to publish customer digital records and track customer communications.
- Automated checks for PDF and XML submissions required by the NRC for new nuclear power licensees.

CAVOK Group/Oliver Wyman, Keller, Texas

Feb 2005 — Dec 2008

Technical Analyst

- Automated the data extraction process for aircraft manufacturer maintenance program information.
- Created tools in Excel for automatic manipulation of data required for loading into custom company software used to track custom aircraft maintenance compliance programs.
- Developed automation to extract and organize manufacturer data from PDFs into editable formats for further refinement and development of custom aircraft maintenance programs.

Education

B.A., University of North Texas

May 2005

 As part of a class project, led a cross-functional team of four Computer Science, Business, and Technical Writing students that developed custom software used to track a company's compliance with training programs.

Contact Information

Mobile: 214-564-0869

Email: aaron@breckenridge.dev

Portfolio: https://www.github.com/breckenedge